David LaRocco

Albuquerque, NM | <u>davidlarocco.dev</u>

SUMMARY

Dedicated, versatile front end web software developer with experience creating applications with HTML, CSS, Javascript, PHP, and React. I bring 15 years of customer service and team-building experience, as well as extensive knowledge of object-oriented programming, REST APIs, data structures, and legacy technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- React.js, jQuery
- Bootstrap, Tailwind, Sass
- Classic ASP, PHP

- Java, Spring Boot
- AWS, Azure
- T-SQL, MS SSMS
- Visual Studio/VS Code

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Maritz | Remote
Interactive Developer (Associate)

January 2024 – current

- Create and maintain dynamic web pages for event registration websites, based on custom client specifications
- Lead development for several high-priority client events, serving as main point of contact for issues onsite
- Coordinate with registration and project managers to meet timelines and resolve issues
- Work with a 5-person team to develop and improve internal documentation standards

Generation USA | Remote

June 2021 – June 2023

Instructor/Teaching Assistant, IT Support Specialist Program & Java Full Stack Developer Program

- Delivered online synchronous modules to a diverse group of learners on software development technologies and
 Object-Oriented Programming concepts
- Oversaw teams in building a full stack web application using Spring Boot, JDBC, JPA, Hibernate, and MySQL
- Troubleshooting issues and provided feedback to learners during asynchronous (independent) learning
- Administered grades and online content with Canvas LMS
- Tailored lessons to provide a personalized learning experience based on grades, assessments, and learner progress

Friend & Company Fine Jewelers | New Orleans, LA Inventory Analyst

April 2018 - March 2020

- Served as the first point of contact for all incoming and outgoing merchandise.
- Documented chain of custody and maintained security controls for high-end jewelry items.
- Improved accuracy and consistency of large database of inventory, customers, and repairs by over 50%
- Created documentation for inventory and shipping procedures

The Chopping Block | Chicago, IL Purchasing Assistant

November 2015 - April 2018

- Created inventory reports and purchase orders to replenish stock for multiple locations.
- Maintained a database of over 2000 items from 100+ vendors.
- Developed buying and merchandising plans that increased sales 10% over previous year.
- Cultivated relationships with vendors and customers
- Wrote the standard operating procedures for the purchasing assistant and wine buyer roles

The Chopping Block | Chicago, IL Retail Trainer

December 2013 - November 2015

- Created, developed, and implemented standardized training procedures for a small team
- Initiated review and redefinition of policies and procedures
- Provided coaching to empower team members to embody the company's core values.
- Deliver excellent customer service and build relationships with customers and associates

CERTIFICATIONS

- CompTIA A+ Certified Professional, 2021
- Google IT Certificate, 2021

EDUCATION

Delgado Community College | New Orleans, LA

A.A.S Computer Information Technology - Programmer/Analyst

June 2020 – May 2022